A Guide to the Papers of Edgar Allan Poe, 1826-1955
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- Series IV: Photographs, Prints and Illustrative Material
  - Statues, Busts, Monuments, Medals
    - Olaf Bjorkman statue of Edgar Allan Poe [ca. 1920], 1 item. Photograph. (Box-folder 2:54)
    - Edith Woodman Burroughs Plaque of Edgar Allan Poe n.d., 1 item. Photograph. (Box-folder 2:55)
      #3565-a
    - Sir Moses Ezekial statue of Edgar Allan Poe n.d., 4 photographs. (Box-folder 2:56)
      "dedicated October 20, 1921 in Wyman Park, Baltimore. Unveiling address by Dr. C. Alphonso Smith." Mounted on 2 cardboard backings. 1 photograph is not attached.
    - Richard H. Park Memorial to Edgar Allan Poe n.d., 3 items. 2 photographs and one diagram (Box-folder 2:57)
      #38-135, #3565-a
    - Edmund J. Quinn bust of Edgar Allan Poe [1907 October 7], 1 item, Photograph. (Box-folder 2:58)
      Mounted. Two signatures: Edmund J. Quinn and Robert B. [Kegereiz?].
    - Zolnay bust of Edgar Allan Poe n.d., 5 items. Photographs, printed material, negatives. (Box-folder 2:59)
      One mounted photograph. Two envelopes contain negative film.
    - Zolnay bust of Edgar Allan Poe n.d., 5 items. Photographs, printed material. (Box-folder 2:60)
      Includes articles regarding Zolnay bust, Poe's Bust has 2 Plaster Companions and Poe Memorial Exercises from the University of Virginia Alumni Bulletin, 1899.
    - Photograph of Edgar Allan Poe Tomb n.d., 1 item. Photograph. (Box-folder 2:61)
    - Photograph of Jane Stanard Monument n.d., 1 item. Photograph. (Box-folder 2:62)
    - Medal commemorating the 100th anniversary of the birth of Edgar Allan Poe 1909, 1 medal. (Box-folder 2:63)
      #9405-f
    - Centenaire d'Edgar A. Poe 1949, 1 medal. (Box-folder 2:64)
      #4178-a
  - Illustrations of Works
    - Illustrations and miscellaneous scenes from Edgar Allan Poe's works and life n.d., 10 items. Engravings and Printed material. (Box-folder 2:65)
    - Engravings from the works of Edgar Allan Poe n.d., 17 items. Engravings. (Box-folder 2:66)
  - Persons and Places associated with Edgar Allan Poe
    - Engraving of John Allan n.d., 1 item. Portrait. (Box-folder 2:67)
    - Silhouette of John Allan; engraving and printed photograph of the Southern Literary Messenger building n.d., 1 item. (Box-folder 2:68)
      3 images atttached to one loose-leaf page. Annotated. #3857-d
    - Engraving of Virginia Clemm Poe n.d., 2 items. Photographs. (Box-folder 2:69)
      Two copies.
    - Pictures of persons and places associated with Edgar Allan Poe n.d., Photographs, newspaper articles, printed material. (Box-folder 2:70)
      #2253
    - Engraving of James Thomson n.d., 1 engraving. (Box-folder 2:71)
      Based on photograph taken in 1869. #38-135
    - Etching of Edgar Allan Poe's school at Stoke Newington, England n.d., 3 items. Engraving and newsclipping. (Box-folder 2:72)
      Two copies of engraving; newsclipping of partial John H. Ingram quotation. #38-135
    - Etchings of Edgar Allan Poe's school at Stoke Newington n.d., 3 items. Etchings and photograph. (Box-folder 2:73)
    - Brick from Southern Literary Messenger building while Edgar Allan Poe was editor n.d., 1 brick. (Box-folder 2:74)
      #957-b